妮卡？
Nica?
- 妮卡 有人在敲门 - 我正忙呢
- Nica. There's somebody at the door. - I'm busy.
妮卡 快开门去…
Nica, please.
天啊
God!
你在干什么呢 那么重要？
What are you doing that's so important?
我在玩纸牌呢
I was playing solitaire.
你知道 电脑上那些东西都是假的
The computer cheats, you know.
好吧 我早就习惯了
Yeah, well, I'm used to that.
- 早上好 - 嗨
- Morning. - Hi.
莎拉·皮尔斯女士的快递
Got a delivery for Mrs. Sarah Pierce?
- 我来签收吧 - 好的
- I'll sign for it. - Cool.
感觉你不像结过婚的人
You know, you don't look like a Mrs.
哦 我…
Oh I'm…
不是我 这是给我妈妈的
I'm not. It's for my mother.
哦 天啊 我也正准备搬回去和我妈妈住呢
Oh, God. I'm back living with my mother, too.
这就是个噩梦 对吧？
It's just a fucking nightmare, right?
你根本不知道
You have no idea.
等等 我的天啊
Wait a minute. Oh, my God.
- 我见过你 - 见过我？
- I know you. - You do?
是啊 城市大学
Yeah, yeah. It was City College.
心理系的 对吧？
The Psych Department, right?
当年在那
That was me.
哦 那你什么时候毕业的？
Well, when'd you graduate?
我没有 我没有完成我的论文
I didn't. I never completed my thesis.
什么课题？
On what?
「成功的渴望」
Completion anxiety.
以为只有男生会那样呢
Thought only guys got that.
所以你妈妈现在在家里了？
So, is your mom home now or what?
是的
Yeah.
那太糟了
Too bad.
好吧 回头见
Well, see you around.
拜
Bye.
- 刚才他是在和我搭讪？ - 宝贝儿 你真是太漂亮了
- Was that guy hitting on me? - Baby, you're beautiful.
谢谢 不过我还是觉得他在和我搭讪
Thank you. But I think that guy was hitting on me.
- 或许我该追出去问问 - 妮卡
- Maybe I should go ask him out. - Nica.
他只是看起来还不错
He was just being nice.
对不起
I'm sorry.
亲爱的 我只是不想看到你受伤害
Honey, I just don't ever want to see you get hurt.
我觉得你应该抛弃这家庭购物网
I thought you swore off the Home Shopping Network.
这几周我没有买过任何东西
I haven't bought anything in three weeks.
或许你有个神秘的追求者
Maybe you have a secret admirer.
- 这听着像是威胁 - 不 绝对没
- You sound threatened. - No. Not at all.
我只是不想看到你受伤害
I just wouldn't want to see you get hurt.
哪来的？
Who's it from?
没注明
It doesn't say.
一定是谁的恶作剧
Must be some kind of joke.
- 我不明白 - 我也不明白
- I don't get it. - Neither do I.
他很可爱
He's cute.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
我是恰吉 想来玩么？
I'm Chucky. Wanna play?
艾莉丝会喜欢他的
Alice will love him.
我才去录制了家庭主妇
I DVR'd Real Housewives.
我等下再去做金枪鱼三明治 行吗？
I'm going to make tuna melts later. Okay?
妈？
Mom?
我的天啊
Oh, God.
妈妈 不
Mom! No.
我需要一辆救护车 马上 是我妈妈
I need an ambulance right away. It's my mother.
我不知道 我不知道 这里有太多血了
I don't know. I don't know. There's so much blood.
《鬼娃回魂6：鬼娃的诅咒》
妮卡
Nica.
对不起
I'm sorry.
她本来好好的
She was fine.
她吃过药以后 又开始画画了
She was taking her meds, she was painting again.
- 不 不 - 她本来好好的
- No. No. - She was fine.
她怎么会这样 芭比？
How could she do that, Barbie?
她怎么能这样对她自己呢？
How could she do that to herself?
你记得的弗兰克神父
You remember Father Frank.
是的 你好 神父
Yes. Hello, Father.
对于她的逝去我深表遗憾 妮卡
I'm so very sorry for your loss, Nica.
谢谢
Thank you.
你姐姐认为我来了或许有用
Your sister just thought it might be a good idea for me to come.
我非常感激
I appreciate it.
但是你知道我妈妈和我都很久都没去做礼拜了
But you know my mother and I both left the church a long time ago.
但上帝不在意
But not in the eyes of God.
我觉得和其他人谈谈对我们会好点
I just thought it might be nice for us to have someone to talk to.
我们拥有彼此
We have each other.
妮卡
Nica.
我们必须为她祈祷 让她被原谅
We have to pray for her. To be forgiven.
她只是生病了 你不能责备她
She was sick. You can't judge her.
没有人会责备她
No one is judging her.
事实上 教会对这样的情况一般这样答复
In fact, the church's official response to a situation like this
不是去责备 而是去怜悯
is not to judge, but to pity.
母亲和我已经得到足够的怜悯了 谢谢
My mother and I have had quite enough pity, thank you.
我知道了
I understand.
这是我的错
It was my fault.
我应该看到事情发生的
I should have seen it coming.
妮卡 你不用责怪你自己
Nica, you cannot blame yourself.
她本来就是被你照顾着的
She was supposed to be taking care of you.
- 嘿 - 嘿 伊恩
- Hey. - Hey, Ian.
拥抱一下
Gimme a hug.
- 这是把新的轮椅？ - 是的
- Is that a new chair? - Yeah.
- 不错哦 - 谢谢
- It's cool. - Thank you.
这是吉尔 我的新的互惠生
This is Jill, my new au pair.
- 不 我就是保姆 - 你好
- No, I'm just the nanny. - Hi.
我很抱歉 妮卡
I'm so sorry, Nica.
谢谢 我很高兴你们能来这里
Thank you. I'm glad you're here.
快过来这里
Come here, you.
- 我很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- I'm so happy to see you. - Me, too.
外婆去天堂了么？
Did Grandma go to heaven?
是的 亲爱的 她去天堂了
Yes, sweetie, she did.
嘿 我有个惊喜给你
Hey, I have a surprise for you.
很有趣
That's funny.
妈咪 我要去洗手间
Mommy, I have to go to the bathroom.
好的 吉尔会带你去的
Okay. Jill will take you.
你带她去 妈咪需要陪妮卡姨妈谈谈
You show her the way. Mommy needs to talk to Aunty Nica.
吉尔 走吧
Jill, let's go.
我想和他们一起去 好吗？
I think I'm going to go with them. Okay?
记住 你们不能锁门
Remember, you don't have to lock the door.
- 但是或许会有人进来 - 我们不会让任何人进来的
- But somebody might come in. - We won't let anybody in.
但这些人呢？
But what about you guys?
亲爱的 我们真的不想看你做自己的事情的
Honey, we really don't want to see you do your business.
好吧 再见
Okay, bye.
听着 她给你多少钱？
So listen, how much is she paying you again?
一周400美金
$400 a week.
这超过了我自己挣的
That's more than I make.
好吧 不过你或许应该考虑改变下事业方向了
Well, maybe you should consider a career change.
嘿 我是个伟大的保姆 一周400美金啊
Hey, I'd be a great nanny. $400 a week!
- 嘿 - 额 不过没有福利
- Man. - Yeah, but no benefits.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
艾莉丝？ 艾莉丝 打开门 亲爱的
Alice? Alice, open the door, honey!
艾莉丝 马上打开门
Alice? Alice, open the door right now.
他把我吓得半死
He scared me half to death.
（「黎明之日」 伤残者的生活辅助）
这是什么？
What is this?
那个 妈妈把房子留给了我们俩
Well, Mom left the house to both of us.
- 然后呢？ - 然后
- So? - So.
我觉得我们应该考虑把它卖掉
I think we should consider selling.
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
妮卡 这地方是不错
Nica, this place is fabulous.
我们会离得更近一些
It's so much closer to us,
也会更加方便见到你
we'd get to see you way more often.
你拿走我们卖掉房子的一半的钱
And with your half of what we could get for the house,
你就可以安享余生了
you'd be set for the rest of your life.
这不关我的事 这是钱的事
This isn't about me. This is about money.
你知道我们一直在辛苦
Well, you know we've been struggling.
平面媒体要消亡了
Print media is dead.
伊恩现在在星巴克工作
Ian's working at Starbucks.
我们也不得不准备送艾莉丝去公立学校上学
We're going to have to send Alice to public school.
而且她想去圣布里奇特上学已经想很久了
And she so had her heart set on St. Bridget's.
我不想失去我的孩子
I don't want to deprive my child.
你都有家住的保姆
You have a live-in nanny.
嗯 事实上 这是不是真的工作
Well, actually, that's not really working out.
巴波 这也是我的房子
Barb, this is my home.
妮卡 我知道这很艰难
Nica, I know this is hard.
不过你真的认为你能独自拥有这里么？
But do you really think you can manage here all by yourself?
妈妈本来想你来照顾她的
Mom would have wanted you to be taken care of.
这是他想要的一切
That's all she ever wanted.
我们回来了
We're back.
- 你找到了他 - 他在洗手间里面
- You found him. - He was in the bathroom.
是吗？
Really?
你知道的 我认为外婆是想让你来照顾他的
You know, I think Grandma would have wanted you to take care of him.
这东西被送到这显然是个错误
It was obviously sent here by mistake.
他应该是别人的
It must belong to someone else.
艾莉丝 你已经有太多这样的娃娃了
And Alice, you already have too many dolls as it is.
对啊 不过恰吉会是我朋友直到永远
Yeah, but Chucky's my friend till the end!
我真的觉得这是个很好的礼物
I actually think it's a really nice gesture.
谢谢 妮卡姨妈
Thank you, Aunty Nica.
一个娃娃
It's a doll.
还有什么能比这更糟？
What's the worst that can happen, huh?
我喜欢被拥抱
I like to be hugged.
我也喜欢抱你 恰吉
I like to hug you, too, Chucky.
那是什么 恰吉？
What's that, Chucky?
恰吉想知道晚餐吃什么？
Chucky wants to know what's for dinner.
我猜最好在厨房开始
I guess I better get started in the kitchen.
不要傻了
Don't be silly.
你们是我的客人 你们坐飞机肯定是累坏了
You guys are my guests and you must be exhausted from your flight,
就像在自己家里一样吧
please just make yourselves at home.
弗兰克神父 你会留下来吃晚餐的 是吗？
Father Frank, you will stay for dinner, won't you?
好的 妮卡 谢谢
Well, I'd love to, Nica. Thanks.
你去准备晚餐吧 6人份
You're going to make dinner. For six.
7人份
Seven.
好吧 我需要一个打下手的
Well, I will need a chef's assistant.
恰吉能作为我的助手
And Chucky can be my assistant.
好吧 我们开始做饭
Great. Let's get cooking.
- 这味道真不错 - 这是牛至
- It's really good. - It's the oregano.
- 你吧餐具摆好了么？ - 差不多了
- Did you finish setting the table? - Almost.
- 给小费 - 我们势如破竹
- Pay the toll. - We're on a roll.
（老鼠药）
不 亲爱的 别碰它 你能给我拿些纸巾么？
No, honey, don't touch that. Can you grab me the napkins?
去年圣诞看中的
The fancy ones from last Christmas.
闻起来棒极了
This smells delicious.
- 谢谢 - 开吃吧 恰吉
- Thanks. - Come on, Chucky.
看看这些 妮卡
Look at this, Nica.
这段时间你做的很棒
You've really outdone yourself this time.
我们要坐在这里
We are going to sit right here.
- 巴波 过来坐我旁边 - 好吧 如果你坚持的话
- Barb, sit next to me here. - Okay. If you insist.
- 看看这个 - 谢谢你 吉尔 别客气 请随便坐
- Look at this. - Thanks, Jill. Make yourself comfortable.
你把这么好的瓷器都拿出来了
You brought out the nice china.
神父 你想做饭前祷告吗？
Father, would you like to say grace?
上帝保佑我们 求你降福我们
Bless us, oh Lord, and these Thy gifts
并降褔你惠赐的这次晚餐
which we are about to receive from Thy bounty.
- 住手 - 向我们的主耶稣基督祈祷
- Stop. - Through Jesus Christ our Lord we pray.
阿门
Amen.
- 来一点吗？ - 谢谢你 伊恩
- Jill? - Thank you, Ian.
- 别介意我喝酒 - 你喝不喝 神父？
- Don't mind if I do. - How about you, Father?
不用 喝水就行了
No. I'm good.
我饿极了
I am starving.
等等
Wait.
你爸爸想先说个敬酒词
Your daddy would like to make a toast.
敬这位厨师
To the chef.
谢谢你 我可是有一个好助手呢
Thank you. I had a great assistant.
- 我喜欢吃辣的 - 你真的爱吃？
- I love chili. - Do you really?
- 当然 - 我也是 我可喜欢了
- Yeah. - Me, too. Love it.
- 这里面带肉吗？ - 没有
- Is there meat in this? - No. Not at all.
是素食
It's vegetarian.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
- 我的天啊 - 怎么了？
- Oh, my God. - What?
这真是太好吃了
This is amazing!
是啊 我简直不敢相信这里面居然没肉
I know. I can't believe there's no meat in this.
这顿饭太丰盛了
It's so hearty.
因为里面有牛至叶粉
It's the oregano.
我妈妈以前就是这么做的
This is just the way my mama used to make it.
妮卡 可以帮忙把盐递过来吗？
Nica, could you pass me the salt?
谢谢
Thank you.
不知为什么 这个玩偶看起来挺眼熟的
You know, that doll, it looks really familiar somehow.
神父 别开玩笑了
Father, come on.
好人娃娃在八十年代风靡一时
Good Guy dolls were all the rage back in the 80s.
- 我哥哥也有一个呢 - 我也是
- My brother even had one. - So did mine.
- 你说真的吗？ - 当然
- Are you serious? - Yes.
哦 得了吧
Oh, come on.
我好像在新闻里见过他们
I seem to remember seeing them on the news?
我记得看见人们大半夜的排队
I remember seeing people standing in line overnight
就是为了抢购到各种娃娃
just to get their hands on one of these.
它们和蓝精灵与卷心菜娃娃摆放在一起
They were right up there with Smurfs and Cabbage Patch Kids.
- 艾莉丝 有什么不对的地方吗？ - 味道感觉很奇怪
- Alice, honey, is something wrong? - It tastes funny.
也许是因为牛至叶粉放多了
Maybe we put too much oregano in.
艾莉丝 小乖乖 其实没那么糟糕
Alice, sweetheart, it's not that bad.
吃吧
Eat it.
神父 你没事吧？
Father, are you all right?
我很抱歉 我要离开下
I'm so sorry, I'm going to have to be going.
- 我的天啊 神父 你生病了吗？ - 没事 我很好
- Oh, my God, Father, are you ill? - Oh, no, I'm fine.
我要回教堂去赴一个预约
I have an appointment back at the church.
妮卡 谢谢你 辣椒饭很美味
Nica, thank you so much, the chili was delicious.
- 神父 你没事吧？ - 没事 请原谅我
- Father, are you? - No, please forgive me.
我不是想贸然离开
I don't mean to be rude.
明早我们墓地见
I'll see you all in the morning at the cemetery.
晚安
Good night.
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
- 他在哪儿？ - 这边走
- Where is he? - This way.
- 发生了什么事情？ - 车辆失控 车头被撞烂了
- What happened? - Lost control, hit them head on.
或许是因为醉驾
Probably drunk.
不 这不可能 我认识他 我跟他的教区内
No, no, this isn't right. I know him, I'm in his parish.
- 他已经戒酒了 - 你对此确认吗？
- He doesn't drink anymore. - You sure about that?
他是我的教父
He's my sponsor.
斯坦顿 看到这个后 你就会需要喝一杯了
Stanton, you're going to need a drink after you see this.
天哪
Jesus Christ.
钢铁直接插入了他的身体 他流了好多血
Steel's got him pinned. He's lost a shitload of blood,
但我们却找不到具体位置
but we just can't tell from where.
神父 你能听到我的声音吗？神父？
Father, can you hear me? Father?
坚持一会儿 我们现在救你出来
Just hang on! We're going to get you out.
你们他妈的在等什么？快把这些东西挪开
What the hell are you waiting for? Get this shit off him!
我做不了这个决定
I can't make that call.
他血都快流干了 救他出来
He's bleeding to death! Get him out!
- 好吧 准备好 - 听我倒计时
- Okay, set in. - On my count.
一 二 拉
One, two, pull.
这绝对是一部老片子
This is an oldie.
我的天呀 这是你吗？
Oh, my God. Is that you?
- 闭嘴 - 你好可爱
- Shut up. - You're so cute.
这就叫婴儿肥
It's called baby fat.
我可什么都没说啊
Look, I didn't say anything.
- 快回去睡觉 - 我会的
- Go back to sleep. - Will do.
你看看她
Look at her.
她可开心了
She's so happy.
你爸爸出了什么事啊？
What happened to your dad?
那一年他淹死了
He drowned that year,
就在妮卡出生的几个月前
couple of weeks before Nica was born.
从那以后妈妈就像变了个人一样
Mom was never the same after that.
他是谁？
Who's that?
我猜 是在芝加哥的邻居吧
Some neighbor back in Chicago, I guess.
真是一个怪人
What a weirdo.
- 嘿 小姐 有何贵干？ - 恰吉不见了
- Hey there, missy, what'cha up to? - Chucky's gone.
- 又来 - 你最后把他放在哪了呀？
- Not again. - Well, where did you leave him?
我没有放 是他藏起来的
I didn't. He's hiding.
好吧 睡觉时间到
Okay, time for bed.
不要忘记刷牙和梳头
And don't forget to brush your teeth and your hair.
- 那恰吉怎么办？ - 吉尔会去找恰吉的
- What about Chucky? - Jill will go look for Chucky.
- 我去帮你找 吉尔 - 我们还没看完呢
- I'll give you a hand, Jill. - We're not done here yet.
我猜他藏在我床下
I think he's hiding under my bed.
别担心 我们会找到他的
Don't worry, we'll find him.
我出去一下 马上回来
I'm going to be right back.
（没有信号）
你确定你没有把它丢在楼下吗？
Are you sure you didn't leave him downstairs?
我真的没有把他丢下 是他自己藏起来的
I didn't leave him anywhere. He's hiding.
他在那里
There he goes!
我可没心情跟你玩这个
I am not in the mood for this.
- 需要我帮忙吗？ - 我他妈真需要一个寻物大队
- Need a hand? - I need a fucking search party!
我翻遍了整栋屋子
I have looked over every inch of this house
但我就是找不到他
and I can't find him anywhere.
- 天啊 我一直在想你 - 闭嘴
- God, I've missed you. - Shut up.
你找到他了
You found him.
我猜是姐姐希望让你找到他
I think she wanted you to find him.
你知道的 我跟她在一起的时间不够多
You know, I haven't been spending enough time with her.
似乎我一停止工作 我就会一直疲惫不堪
It's like if I'm not working, I'm just so tired all the time.
生命是短暂的
Life is short!
- 他们总是那么说吗？ - 我也不知道
- Did they always say that? - I don't know.
听着 小人儿 你到底在背后
Listen, little man, what else are you,
跟我孩子说了什么？
telling my kid behind my back, huh?
我喜欢被拥抱
I like to be hugged.
- 还有呢？ - 想玩吗？
- And? - Wanna play?
- 就完了？ - 你好 我叫恰吉
- Is that it? - Hi. I'm Chucky.
我是你一辈子的好朋友
And I'm your friend till the end.
这句话可是经典
That one's a classic.
而且对各种各样的人都管用
And it works on so many different levels.
是啊 八十年代的人都很棒
Yeah, the 80s were awesome.
你们找到他了吗？
Did you find him yet?
没错 我们找到他啦
Yeah, we found him!
我带他上去
I'll take him up.
伊恩？
Ian?
有人吗？
Anyone?
喂？
Hello?
该死的
Oh, shit.
我来了
Coming!
看吧 她一在 就有坏事发生
See, with her, it's always something.
她接受我的帮助 然后就就此对我发脾气
She needs my help and then resents me for it.
只有你才会真心感谢我
You're the only one who really appreciates me.
你知道吗 我在想
You know, I was thinking.
我们没钱也一样可以生活下去
We can get by without the money.
你不用把房子卖掉
You don't have to sell.
我的意思是 这可是她的家呢
I mean, this is her home.
她就是一烂摊子 你也看到了
She's a mess. You can see that.
太可怕了
Oh, crap.
原来你在这 恰吉
There you are, Chucky!
我们找了你好久了
We've been looking for you everywhere.
嘿 想玩吗？
Hey, want to play?
我没想到你可以这样
I didn't know you could do that.
游戏时间结束 现在是睡觉时间
Playtime's over. It's time for bed.
你能给我们讲个睡前故事吗？
Can you read us a bedtime story?
妮卡姨妈累了 宝贝 我们得让她休息了
Aunty Nica's tired, sweetie. We'll let her rest now.
我不累
I'm fine.
你还是别勉强自己了
It's important that you don't overextend yourself.
难道你不认为我才有权判断自己是否在勉强吗？
Don't you think I'm the best judge of when I'm overextending myself?
- 坦白地说 我真不这样认为 - 是吗
- Frankly, no. - Really.
我认为你还没意识到你现在多紧张
I don't think you realize the strain you're under.
承认下你需要帮助又不难的
There's no shame in admitting that you need help.
你是说需要「协助」吧
You mean "assistance."
妮卡 我是在担心的的心脏 好吗？
Nica, I am worried about your heart. Okay?
马苏尔医生说过我没事的 巴波
Dr. Masur said I was fine, Barb.
你复发的可能性不可忽视 你知道的
You're at significant risk of it happening again, you know that.
- T5瘫痪者中的百分之十三… - 我懂统计学
- 13% of all T5 paraplegics… - I know the statistics.
马苏尔医生说过极端的压力
Dr. Masur said that extreme stress,
哪怕是轻微的刺激都会导致心脏病复发
any kind of even mild shock could bring it on.
昨晚到现在 上帝都明白你已经经历了太多
And since last night, God knows you've had plenty of both.
艾莉丝 宝贝 快从上面下来
Alice, sweetheart, please come down from there.
我虽然残疾了 巴波 不过我已经不是个孩子了
I'm disabled, Barb, I am not a child.
我可以极好地照顾好我自己的事
And I'm perfectly capable of taking care of myself.
妮卡姨妈 你出血了
Aunty Nica, you're bleeding.
- 噢 天哪 - 我自己处理 好不？
- Oh, my God. - I got it. Okay?
看起来像刀割过的伤口
It almost looks like a knife wound.
你肯定是做饭的时候割到了自己
You must have cut yourself making dinner.
- 我没割到自己 - 疼吗？
- I didn't. - Doesn't it hurt?
不 不疼 别担心 宝贝
No. No, don't worry, sweetie.
她感觉不到疼的
She can't feel a thing.
好了 快点 现在快去床上睡觉
All right, come on. Come on. Off to bed now.
晚安 妮卡姨妈
Good night, Aunty Nica.
晚安 宝贝 做个好梦
Good night, baby. Sweet dreams.
我躺下睡着了
Now I lay me down to sleep,
我祈祷上帝请保管好我的灵魂
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
如果还没醒来就将死去
If I shall die before I wake,
祈祷上帝将我的灵魂静静地带走
I pray the Lord my soul to take.
上帝保佑外婆 妈妈 爸爸 和吉尔
God bless Grandma, and Mommy, and Daddy, and Jill.
尤其保佑妮卡姨妈
And especially Aunty Nica.
不保佑恰吉？
What about Chucky?
他说他不相信上帝
He says there is no God.
- 谁说过这话？ - 恰吉说的
- Who said that? - Chucky did.
他说过人生无常 当你死的时候
He said that life's a bitch and then you die,
血流地像头被宰的猪一样
bleeding like a stuck pig.
艾莉丝 这样诅咒是不对的
Alice. You know it's not nice to curse.
我没诅咒 妈妈 是恰吉
I don't curse, Mommy. Chucky did.
妈妈 我会死吗？
Mommy, am I going to die?
不 当然不会 宝贝儿
No. Of course not, sweetie.
外婆死了 恰吉说我们全部都得死
Grandma died. And Chucky says we're all going to die.
艾莉丝 到底是谁跟你说的这些？
Alice, who really told you that?
- 是吉尔吗？ - 不是
- Was it Jill? - No.
- 是你爸吗？ - 不 是恰吉说的
- Was it your daddy? - No, it was Chucky.
好吧
Okay.
今晚我们可以跟你一起睡吗？
Can't we sleep in with you tonight?
艾莉丝 我们说好的呀 你现在是个大孩子
Alice, we've talked about this. You're a big girl now.
只不过是暴风雨罢了
It's only a storm.
吉尔一会就来了
And Jill's going to be in in a while.
还有恰吉也要
Don't forget Chucky!
别害怕 恰吉 这仅仅是场暴雨
Don't worry, Chucky. It's only a storm.
女士 谢谢您的来电 你查询的包裹…
Ma'am, thank you for holding. The package…
物证保管处
Evidence depository.
很抱歉 信号断断续续
I'm sorry, you're breaking up.
你刚说的是「物证保管处」？
Did you say "evidence depository"?
喂？你还在吗？
Hello? Hello, are you there?
恰吉 我很害怕
Chucky, I'm scared.
你他妈的不害怕才怪
You fucking should be.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们找到娃娃了
We found him.
- 她真的喜欢那娃娃 - 恩 她的确喜欢
- She sure loves that thing. - Yeah. She sure does.
不过呢 我刚给快递公司打了电话
But you know, I just called the delivery company,
电话里说娃娃是从一个物证保护处寄来的
and they said it was sent from an evidence depository.
就像那种犯罪现场物证？
As in crime scene evidence?
我不知道 可能我听错了 信号不好
I don't know. Maybe I heard them wrong. The connection was bad.
肯定是这样了
I'm sure that's it.
恩 但仍然不知道到底是谁寄来的
Yeah, but we still don't know who sent it.
我不关心它是否属于曼森家的
I don't care if it was the Manson Family.
任何能让孩子开心的东西对我来说都无所谓
Anything that keeps her this happy is fine by me.
她最近一直很伤心的样子
She's been so sad lately.
我最好去睡觉了 明天还很长
I better get to bed. Long day tomorrow.
- 晚安 - 晚安 吉尔
- Good night. - Good night, Jill.
（恰吉 娃娃 物证）
（芝加哥三重杀人案 未侦破）
（星期四 十二月二十九日 1988年）
（娃娃受到诅咒吗？ 孩子说是恰吉干的！）
（安迪·巴克利 6岁）
安迪·巴克利
Andy Barclay.
（视频通话等待接通）
（连环杀手被枪杀）
（查尔斯·李·雷死在芝加哥玩具店里）
查尔斯
Charles.
她起床了
She's up.
（查尔斯·李·雷 搜索图片）
女人
Women.
无法忍受和她们在一起 就是这样
Can't live with 'em. Period.
靠
Shit.
- 怎么了？ - 又停电了
- What's going on? - Power's out again.
我要去看下艾莉丝
I'm going to go check on Alice.
那吉尔呢？
What about Jill?
- 吉尔怎么了？ - 喂 巴波
- What about her? - Well, come on, Barb.
你每周花四百块钱让她照顾好我们的孩子
You're paying her $400 a week to take care of our kid.
你难道还不相信她能自己搞定？
Don't you think she can handle it?
伊恩 她会怕黑的
Ian, she's afraid of the dark.
外面是暴风雨 孩子可能需要我
It's storming out. She might need me.
到底是 谁需要你？
Who, exactly, might need you?
你觉得呢？
Who do you think?
现在我不知道我该怎么去想
Right now I'm not sure what to think.
这个…
You know…
别用你恶心的幻想来暗示我 行不？
Don't try to implicate me in your sick fantasies, okay?
我已经发现你看待她的方式了
I've seen the way you look at her.
同感
Ditto.
伊恩 我和保姆没一腿
Ian, I am not sleeping with the nanny.
当然不了 你不至于这么蠢 巴波
No, of course, you couldn't be that stupid, Barb.
明知道如果我可以证明你们在乱搞的话
Knowing that if I could prove such a thing,
我可以轻易地从你身边带走艾莉丝
I could easily take Alice away from you.
或者我可以找找视频
Or I could just check the footage.
你在说啥？
What are you talking about?
保姆监视器拍下的视频
The footage from the nanny cam.
- 什么保姆监视器？ - 今天我藏了一个到娃娃里
- What nanny cam? - The one I hid in the doll today.
你休想抢走我女儿 你听清楚了没？
You are not taking my daughter away from me. Do you hear me?
我不会让你毁掉这个家的
I am not going to let you destroy this family
就因为你那恶心 偏执的指控
because of your sick, paranoid accusations.
没错 指控我吧
That's right. Tune me out.
让巴波搞定一切
Let Barb take care of everything.
这就是你最常干的 对不？
That's what you always do anyway, right?
你这给人倒咖啡的失败者
You latte-making loser.
取证处有消息没？
What's the word from Forensics?
要等化验血液后才能得到答案
Won't know anything for sure till they cook his blood.
嘿 你和圣保罗教堂的人谈了没？
Hey, you talk to anyone at St. Paul's yet?
有人说他一整天呆在皮尔斯家
Said he was out at the Pierce house all day.
好 可能他们家会知道些什么
Okay, well, maybe they'll have some answers for us.
我现在就过去
I'm going to head out there now.
艾莉丝？
Alice?
艾莉丝 我现在没空跟你玩
Alice! I don't have time to play games.
巴波？
Barb?
巴波
Barb!
- 巴波 艾莉丝在哪？ - 在玩该死的捉迷藏
- Barb, where's Alice? - Playing fucking hide and seek.
巴波 把他放下
Barb, put him down.
你有什么毛病？
What is wrong with you?
听好 我知道这听起来很疯狂 不过那个娃娃
Look, I know that this sounds nuts, but that doll,
我认为有些不干净的东西在里面
I think that there's something in it.
等等 你知道这？
Wait a second. You know about this?
- 我确定 - 你早就知道里面有什么了？
- Well, I think that I do. - You know what's in this?
你知道？
Do you?
你为何原来不跟我讲？
Why didn't you tell me?
- 现在我正和你说啊 - 你何时发现的这个？
- I'm trying to tell you. - Wait, wait. When did you find out?
- 这个很重要？ - 对我来说重要
- What does it matter? - It matters to me.
我自己的亲妹妹在帮人在抓我的把柄当然重要
It matters to me that my own sister is out to get me.
不 不 不 你没理解 这…
No. No, no, no, you don't understand, this…
我很好地理解了
I understand perfectly.
我明白你嫉妒我有个正常人的生活这个事实
I understand you resent the fact that I actually have a life.
不 巴波 不是这样的…
No, Barb, this isn't about anything that…
你知道吗？妮卡？
Well, you know what, Nica?
这不是我的错 好不？
It isn't my fault. Okay?
你身上发生的事不是我的错
What happened to you isn't my fault.
你从学校辍学不是我的错
And it isn't my fault that you dropped out of school,
你无法离开这个鬼地方不是我的错
and it isn't my fault that you chose to never leave this goddamned house.
你到底在等什么 上帝的指示？
I mean, what the hell were you waiting for, a sign from God?
不 巴波 把那个该死的娃娃放下
No, Barb! Just put the fucking doll down!
去你的 妮卡
Fuck you, Nica.
巴波
Barb!
艾莉丝 从这下来
Alice! Get down here!
吉尔？
Jill?
伊恩
Ian!
靠
Shit!
艾莉丝？
Alice?
艾莉丝 别碰任何东西 你听见了没？
Alice, don't touch anything. You hear me?
艾莉丝 你现在麻烦大了 小女士
Alice, you are in big trouble, young lady!
艾莉丝
Alice!
艾莉丝 快出来
Alice, please.
妈咪快对你们感到恶心了
Mommy is just about sick to death of all of you.
艾莉丝？
Alice?
艾莉丝 你现在赶快出来
Alice, you come out here right this minute.
天哪
Oh, my God.
艾莉丝
Alice.
艾莉丝是我的
Alice is mine.
现在她知道了
Now she knows
没有上帝
there is no God.
你眼睛和你妈的一样
You have your mother's eyes.
这双眼TMD离太近了
And they were always too fucking close together!
不
No!
芭比？
Barbie?
妮卡
Nica.
我来找你了
I'm gonna get you.
艾莉丝
Alice!
伊恩 伊恩
Ian! Ian!
伊恩
Ian!
- 伊恩 伊恩 - 什么？
- Ian! Ian! - What?
- 伊恩 他们都死了 - 你在说啥？
- Ian, they're dead! - What are you talking about?
巴波 吉尔 他们都死了 我找不到艾莉丝
Barb, Jill, they're dead, and I can't find Alice!
- 不 不 他还在那里 - 谁？
- No! No! He's still out there! - Who?
恰吉
Chucky!
艾莉丝 艾莉丝
Alice! Alice!
我一定要找到艾莉丝
I gotta go find Alice.
- 伊恩 - 什么？
- Ian! - What?
伊恩 如果你看到恰吉
Ian, if you see Chucky,
无论你在做什么 别去管他
whatever you do, just leave him alone.
恰… 你在说啥？
Chuck… What are you talking about?
一定要离那娃娃远点
Just stay away from that doll!
艾莉丝？
Alice?
伊恩？
Ian?
伊恩
Ian!
艾莉丝？
Alice?
伊恩
Ian!
不会吧
No!
妮卡
Nica!
啊
No!
妮卡 你到底在干什么？
Nica, what the hell are you doing?
是他干的 就是他
He did it! It was him!
妮卡 看着我
Nica! Look at me!
把斧头给我
Give me the ax.
- 什么？不 - 快点 把那该死的斧头给我
- What? No! - Now, give me the goddamn ax!
噢 天啊 妮卡 你做了什么？
Oh, my God. Nica, what have you done?
伊恩 伊恩 求你了 你知道我绝不会…
Ian. Ian, please. You know I would never…
噢 天啊
Oh, my God.
伊恩 伊恩 拿着这个
Ian. Ian. Take this.
帮我注射到肋骨下面
I need you to inject it under my rib.
伊恩
Ian.
伊恩 伊恩 你在干什么？
Ian. Ian, what are you doing?
你到底对我女儿做了什么 妮卡？
What the hell have you done with my daughter, Nica?
- 伊恩 恰吉在哪？ - 你有病啊
- Ian, where's Chucky? - You're sick!
伊恩 我对天发誓 我能证明
Ian, I swear to God, I can prove it!
我也能证明
And so can I.
嗨 巴波 查看一下这个
Hey, Barb, check this out.
无线电器材 450元
RadioShack, 450 bucks.
噢 顺便说一下 如果你在看的话
Oh, and by the way, if you're watching this,
我用的是你的信用卡
I put it on your MasterCard.
你在哪 艾莉丝？
Where are you, Alice?
在这里他们绝不会找到我的 恰吉
They'll never find me in here, Chucky.
这是最好玩的捉迷藏游戏了
This is the best game of hide and seek ever.
只要闭上你那讨厌的嘴就可以了
Just keep your fucking mouth shut.
恰吉 不要乱说了
Chucky, stop cursing.
（现场直播）
替我对小女人问个好
Say hi to the little woman for me.
或许吧
Maybe not.
该你了
Your turn.
该我了
My turn.
你是查尔斯·李·雷
You're Charles Lee Ray.
我的朋友们都叫我恰吉
My friends call me Chucky.
你已经死了
You're dead.
不 你才死了呢
No, you are.
为什么是我们？
Why us?
你们的母亲没有给你们提过我吗？
Didn't your mother ever mention me?
我是你们家的一位老朋友
I'm an old friend of the family.
查尔斯 来这边
Charles, come over here.
我介绍一些人给你
I wanna introduce you to someone.
10月27号
October 27th.
好吧
Okay.
就顶在我的胸腔这里
Right against my rib cage.
很快的 很快就不会这样了
Soon enough. Cannot come soon enough.
查尔斯 这是莎拉
Charles, this is Sarah.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - How do you do?
- 她的丈夫 丹尼尔 - 嗨 先生
- Her husband, Daniel. - Hello, sir.
嗨 丹尼尔 见到你很高兴
Hi, Daniel. Nice to meet you.
这是巴波
And this is Barb.
她的眼睛和她母亲一模一样
She has her mother's eyes.
这么美好 快乐的一家人
Such a nice, happy family.
但是不会持续太久了
But not for long.
你喜欢它们吗？
You like 'em?
很好看 谢谢
They're beautiful, thank you.
它们现在很难找的 不在这个季节盛开
Difficult to find right now. They're not exactly in season.
不管怎么说 我还是喜欢
Anyway, enjoy.
有点晚了
It's gettin' late,
我要去托儿所接芭比了
and I'm gonna go pick up Barbie at day care.
不要
No!
我是说 难道我们不应该留下些单独相处的时间吗？
I mean, shouldn't we have some time alone together?
家庭时间怎么样？
What about family time?
等一会
Later.
现在我只想和你一个人在一块
Right now I want to have you all to myself.
莎拉 莎拉 我整天都在陪着你呢
Sarah. Sarah, you've had me all day.
这还不够
It isn't enough.
对一个母亲来说 这样的态度真是自私
That's a selfish fucking attitude for a mother to take.
你难道不想和我一块抚养她？
You don't wanna share me with her?
不 不是的
No. No.
好吧 等孩子出生了 会发生什么呢？
Well, what's gonna happen when the baby comes?
你难道也要从我身边带走她？因为…
Are you gonna keep her from me, too? Because…
这对我来说 实在太残酷了
that would be very hurtful to me.
你不会看到我受到伤害的 对吗？
And you wouldn't wanna see me get hurt, would you?
对不对？
Would you?
- 对不对？ - 不 不会的
- Would you? - No. No.
我不想看到你受伤害
I don't wanna see you get hurt.
我不想看到任何人受伤害
I don't wanna see anybody get hurt.
好吧
Okay.
我要去接芭比了
I'm gonna go get Barbie.
不 求你了 不要去
No! Please, please! Please don't.
滚 滚啊
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
你告诉他们我们的事了？
You told them about us?
没有我们
There is no us.
为什么？
Why?
你为什么想破坏这个家庭？
Why would you want to destroy this family?
你破坏了我的家庭
You destroyed my family.
没有
No.
我告诉过你
I told you,
我总是有家庭问题
I've always had a thing for families.
不是的
No!
特别是关于孩子的事
Especially kids.
这是你做的？
You did this to me?
不 妮卡 是你非要这样对我的
No, Nica, you did this to me.
你和你的母亲
You and your mommy.
她背叛了我
She betrayed me.
导致我被枪杀
Got me killed.
我知道弥补的办法
But I knew a way to come back.
赐予我力量吧
Give me the power.
求求你了
I beg of you!
花费了我25年
Took me 25 years,
但是相信我
but believe me,
这种等待是值得的
it was worth the wait.
25年
25 years.
从那之后 很多家庭来来往往
Since then, a lot of families have come and gone.
巴克利家 金凯德家 提利家
The Barclays, the Kincaids, the Tillys,
但是妮卡 我最钟爱的还是你的家庭
but Nica, your family was always my favorite.
现在 你是最后一个还活着的
And now, you're the last one standing.
可以这样说
So to speak.
你知道 你让我想起来很多关于安迪·巴克利的事情
You know, you remind me a lot of Andy Barclay.
他是个爱发牢骚的贱货 跟你一样
He was a whiny little bitch, just like you.
你把他也杀了吗？
Did you kill him, too?
可以这样说吧
More or less.
我杀了他的童年
I killed his childhood.
事实上是 我25年之前就杀了你
And the truth is, I killed you 25 years ago.
难道不是吗 妮卡？
Didn't I, Nica?
你从未就没活过
You haven't been living.
我们不能把这叫活着
You can't call this living.
你只是靠设备在维持生命
You've just been on life support.
是时间拔掉那该死的塞子了
Time to pull the fucking plug.
所以你从来就没杀过安迪·巴克利 对吗？
So you never actually killed Andy Barclay, did you?
什么？
What?
你知道吧 这就是所谓的「成功的渴望」
You know, it's called completion anxiety.
这在男性中很常见
It's very common in males.
你是男性 对吗？
You are a male, aren't you?
我会慢慢的折磨死你的
I'm gonna kill you slow.
不用了 我明白了
Yeah, no, I get that.
25年 或许这是历史上最慢性的谋杀了
25 years. Must be the slowest murder in history.
我说 你还在等什么呢？上帝的救赎？
I mean, what are you waiting for? A sign from God?
不是
No!
你感觉到了 对吗？
You feel that, don't ya?
你想玩吗 你个混蛋 那我们就玩吧
You wanna play, motherfucker? Let's play.
警察 开门
Police. Open up.
救命 救命啊
Help! Help me!
基于证据
Based on the evidence,
被告人已宣称没有法定能力
the defendant is declared legally incompetent
并被无限期押回犯罪精神病院里
and remanded indefinitely to a facility for the criminally insane.
我还活着 你这畜生 能听见我说话吗？
I'm alive, you son of a bitch. You hear me?
我还活着
I'm still alive!
请您留言
Please leave a message.
嗨 是我 我在路上了
Hey, it's me. I'm on my way.
不要忘了我的钱
And don't forget my money.
他们绝不会知道的
They never learn.
下一个是谁？
So who's next?
下一个
Next.
下午好
Good afternoon.
三天的 两天的 还是一晚上呢？
Three-day, two-day, or overnight?
一晚上吧 实在太紧急了
Overnight. It's extremely urgent.
易碎吗？
Fragile?
当然不会碎了
Surprisingly not.
大约价值多少呢？
Approximate value?
呃 我妈妈过去常常对我说
Well, my mother always used to say
你不能用金钱去衡量爱
you can't put a price on love.
那就是250美元以内了
Under 250, then.
你给包裹买保险吗？
Would you like to insure the package?
噢 没必要
Oh, that won't be necessary.
保险会保护你和包裹的
It protects you and it protects the recipient.
我表示很怀疑
I doubt that.
易腐烂货物？活着的动物？
Perishable goods? Live animal?
就是「其它」物品
Just put "other."
奶奶 我回来了
Grandma, I'm home.
奶奶？
Grandma?
今天怎么一样啊？
And how are you today?
很好 很开心
Oh, I'm fine. I'm fine.
- 感觉幸运吗？ - 嗯
- Feeling lucky? - Yeah.
太好了 巴尼
Oh, that's great, Bunny.
就像你知道的那样 巴尼赢得了17000…
As you know, Bunny has won 17, 000…
恰吉 你找到我了
Chucky, you found me!
我告诉过你我会找到你的
I told you I would.
奶奶在哪里？
Where's Grandma?
在地下室
In the cellar.
她在下面干什么呢？
What's she doing down there?
什么也没干
Nothin'.
恰吉 妈妈和爸爸死了
Chucky, Mommy and Daddy are dead.
妮卡姨妈杀了他们
Aunty Nica killed them.
我会一直是你的朋友的 艾莉丝
But I'm your friend till the end, Alice.
现在我们可以玩了
And now it's time to play.
捉迷藏？
Hide and seek?
找灵魂
Hide the soul.
猜猜是什么？
And guess what?
就是你
You're it.
为什么非要是我呢？
Why do I always have to be it?
因为你是毋庸置疑的大人物
Because you're somebody that no one would ever suspect.
现在 闭上你的眼睛
Now, close your eyes.
求求你了 赐予我力量
Give me the power, I beg of you.
（六个月后）
- 给你的包裹 - 真的？
- Package for you. - Really?
也许你赢了一些东西
Maybe you won something.
今天一定是我的幸运日
Must be my lucky day.
玩的开心
Have a good one.
谢谢你 你也是
Thanks. You, too.
天啊 一个座椅
Oh, boy. A seat!
不要坐在我的脚上
Get your seat off of my feet.
什么脚？
But what feet?
喂？嗨 妈妈 你怎么样了？
Hello? Oh, hi, Mom, how you doing?
没能给你打电话 真的非常抱歉
I'm sorry I didn't call. I meant to.
明天我一定准时参加你的生日聚会
Yeah, I'm definitely coming for my birthday tomorrow.
嗯 不过不要给我带东西
No, don't get me anything.
求你了 妈妈 不要惊喜 好吗？
Do me a favor, Ma, no surprises, okay?
好的 我会去的 下午？1点？
Yeah. I'll be there, like, noon? 1:00?
晚饭吃什么？
What are you making for dinner?
嗯？
Yeah?
麦克怎么样？
How's Mike doing?
好吧 替我向他问好
Well, tell him I said hello.
嗯
Yeah.
- 好了 - 快点 打开 打开
- All right. - Come on, open up, open up!
到时候见
Well, I'll see you around that time.
好的
Okay.
玩玩这个吧
Play with this.
安迪…
Andy…